[Forging Justice]
[Episode 25]
Gently, gently.
It really hurts that much?
Help me with this side.
Where does it hurt? Seems serious.
T-Touch it.
You perv.
Where is the refrigerator?
I'll get you some ice for the injury.
Over there.
I'm not a perv.
I plan to formally submit a report
to the court
and apply for a review.
I'm done with the underground work.
My job is supposed to be
open and aboveboard.
The court will be happy, won't they?
They will understand sooner or later.
I'm also afraid of progressing too slowly
to keep up with you.
Jianmin...
Recently,
I've been thinking how lucky I am.
God has been so good to me,
as if He is making up for me.
Everything's so great that it actually
scares me
and panics me a little.
Don't fret.
All these good things
are what you deserve.
I...
plan to check out from the hotel.
I'm moving in here with you.
Really?
Really.
Why?
Are you worried
it'll reflect badly on you?
No, I'm not. I-I...
I'm not.
My worry is that it might reflect badly
on you.
Actually, I'd really...
like to have a family.
H-How about we get a marriage
certificate first?
Okay.
Let's get that first.
For real?
What's with you?
I...
Once you hold my hand,
you cannot let go of it.
I won't.
I'll hold it tight for life.
I'll never let go till my life ends.
How am I s-so...
How am I so blessed?
Then why are you crying, lucky man?
Because I'm happy.
Aren't you silly?
No, the wound hurts.
Easy on the food.
You must be starving.
But still, slow down.
Easy, easy.
Wipe your mouth.
Not full, are you?
I'll get you another portion.
No need.
Just stay with me for a while.
But you'll get hungry at night again.
Just stay with me...
Let me save you the trouble.
Take my food here.
Just fetched it. Haven't touched it yet.
That would be inappropriate, Zhang.
Keep it, ma'am. I'll go buy her some.
Just take it.
You two keep chatting.
I'm going out for a walk.
Thanks, Zhang.
No problem.
Shall I bring it over to you?
No need. I'll have it later.
When are you leaving?
Why start with that question
every time I come see you?
Don't get me wrong.
I just don't want to keep you
from any important affairs.
You won't.
Before I came,
I prepared
everything necessary.
And there's a fax machine here.
I won't miss a beat.
Then how long can you stay?
How long do you hope I will stay?
Anything wrong?
Hu Xudong's case
is going to trial.
I'm a little worried.
About what?
About Hu Xudong
turning into another Qian Xingliang.
You're overthinking it.
Besides, it's no use worrying about that,
since it has nothing to do with you.
It does.
I know you're kindly trying to comfort me.
But I won't and I cannot
claim that this case
doesn't concern me.
I get it.
Go back already.
I'll stay here tonight.
When she's discharged tomorrow,
you come pick her up.
I owe you thanks for letting me know
her condition.
N-No need for thanks at all.
I just wish things will work out
between you two.
You see, she's not being
well taken care of here.
The procuratorate
also owes her
due to Qian Xingliang's matter.
After she recovers,
please put in a good word for me.
I heard legal proceedings
have been initiated for that case.
Who told you that?
Was it Yingjie?
Isn't it the reason
she came back here?
The news hasn't reached me yet.
Enough said about me.
Let's talk about you. How are things?
The new Criminal Procedure Law
will be enacted soon.
Haven't you been involved in the revision?
Do offer us
more guidance on work.
We can discuss
professional issues anytime.
I've read through the papers you wrote
in these years.
They are of great reference value.
You wouldn't have been able
to write them so well
without abundant practical experience.
My papers are nothing.
You are truly armed with a doctorate.
You are the one who can really influence
the development of the national law.
Beijing is full of talents,
unlike here.
It's nearly impossible
to find a criminal defense lawyer here
with relevant proficiency.
Hu Xudong's case
is an example.
Hu Xudong
hasn't found a lawyer yet?
Doubtlessly,
he'll surely be assigned a court-appointed
legal aid lawyer.
Remember? "A first-time offender
of a casual nature."
Enough said. Off you go.
Yu.
I'm wondering...
I plan to come back to Binjiang.
Why come back to Binjiang?
What for?
Just for the sake of Binjiang.
Didn't you say
there isn't even
a decent criminal defense lawyer here?
If I were you,
I definitely wouldn't come back.
It's too big a sacrifice.
I don't think of it as a sacrifice.
Do you think I'm not qualified?
You are.
I raise both hands for it.
Your return will bring a balance
between the prosecution and the defense.
Let me walk you out, buddy.
-Are you sure?
-Sure.
You won't drink breast milk
or formula!
What on earth do you want?
Stop crying!
I'm begging you.
I'm begging you!
Xiaowen.
Your mom sent me over
to visit you and Peipei.
J-Just consider me
a delivery person.
Look.
This is imported baby formula.
I...
I had it brought back from Hong Kong
by someone.
It costs several hundred yuan a can.
I have to work on two cases to afford...
Xiaowen.
P-Please let me
see my grandson.
Xiaowen.
Xiaowen!
I just want to remind you
to take your time with the baby.
Be patient.
Patience is a must.
I'll leave the formula
on the cabinet by the door.
I'm taking off now.
Remember...
to bring it home quickly.
Or it'll go missing again.
Who are you looking for?
Hand it out!
Hand out what?
You also took the items last time,
didn't you?
What do you mean by that?
You must be delutional.
Listen up,
I'm a lawyer.
And I'm a chef!
You think you can scare me?
That imported baby formula and 3,000 yuan
are my gifts for my daughter.
What do I have to do with the gifts
you got your daughter?
Now you are a repeat offender.
According to Article 151
and 152 of the Criminal Law,
and the Notice on Adjusting
the Threshold Amounts for Theft
Offenses issued by the Supreme Court
and the Supreme Procuratorate,
your actions constitute a theft case
involving a large sum of money.
I...
Notice? What notice?
And now I can also sue you for assault!
To hell with that!
Scram!
It doesn't hurt.
I deserve this.
Slow down. Be gentle!
I already told you
you were mistaken.
I didn't do it.
It wasn't me!
How was I supposed to know he'd collapse
after just one punch?
Don't push me!
Gentler, the two of you!
I know! Just don't push!
Pei!
Don't cry, Peipei.
Everything's fine.
Grandpa is just going to make a statement.
Then I'll be home.
My dear daughter,
I'm so delighted today.
Thank you for bandaging my wound.
Today's
beating was worth it.
I even want to
thank that couple.
I'm leaving then.
Goodbye, Pei! See you later!
This place is absolutely ridiculous.
The car I booked earlier
suddenly bailed on me,
so I had to take a long-distance bus.
Cancel the trip?
How can I cancel the trip?
That scam company
swindled over two million out of me.
How can I let them get away?
Yes, in Nanyu, exactly.
Nanyu is a hell
of a place.
How do I find them?
I don't know a single soul there.
In a small town like this,
I doubt if there's even a lawyer.
Anyway, the first thing I'll do
when I arrive
is try my luck
at the police station
and then the courthouse.
I'm hanging off now.
I'll call you back later.
Bye.
What do you want?
Did you just say
you need a lawyer in Nanyu
for a financial dispute?
You understand Cantonese?
My grandfather is from Conghua.
Who are you?
I am a lawyer.
The best lawyer in Nanyu.
My name is Qin Zhigao.
[Nanyu Jianzheng Law Firm,
Lawyer Qin Zhigao]
Hello. Anyone in there?
Coming!
Hello.
Who are you looking for?
This is
Wang Danni's home, right?
Yes.
Hello.
I'm Lyu Siyi's father.
I'd like a word with Wang Danni
about the case.
Please wait a moment.
How dare you come here,
you murderer!
This serves you right!
Murder!
There's a murder!
How about you wait outside
while I go in by myself?
Okay.
Otherwise,
we might come across as too eager.
Right.
We're simply paying a visit.
I'm afraid he might misinterpret this.
I'm off then.
I'll be waiting here for you!
Take a seat somewhere.
Captain Lyu.
How are your ribs?
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
All I need is a bit of rest.
Sorry, Captain Lyu.
I failed to catch him that day.
Don't say that.
I'm the one who owes you.
You came all the way here
to ask about that matter, right?
There is indeed a matter.
Those silly boys of yours had me ask you
when the arcade will open.
Captain Lyu, take care of your daughter.
I'm getting going.
Alright, no need to beat around the bush.
You see what condition
my daughter is in.
Now, I can
tell you explicitly
that I'm in no mood
to help with
Yan Jicai's case anymore.
That said, to this day, I still believe
Yan Jicai cannot be ruled out
as a murder suspect.
So he's a suspect now,
not a murderer anymore?
Don't play word games with me.
Got it.
I'll see you sometime
later then.
Thank you.
Also, please say thank you
to Prosecutor Zhang for me.
I really mean it.
Okay.
How did it go?
Did he bring that thing up?
He mentioned it himself
and said he had no time for it.
It's okay.
Let's go talk to Zhou Pu and Qiao Xiaojun.
Sure.
What's wrong?
The postman. I missed the postman.
What postman?
Why would you wait for him?
For the registered letter.
What's with it?
Didn't you ask Mr. Guo
to send over the household register
and a letter of introduction?
How else can we get
a marriage certificate?
What's wrong with you?
I thought I missed
out on some details.
You gave me a fright.
What? Do you regret it now?
No!
[Binjiang People's Procuratorate]
Yizhong.
Mentor.
You like
peaches, right?
They are in season,
so I brought you some.
Great. Thank you.
Sit down.
Have you decided?
Yes.
Now, I just need to
persuade my teacher and my dad
when I get home.
It's not a bad idea.
For you, returning to Binjiang
is like reclaiming lost land.
How is that so?
In terms of reclaiming lost land,
I'd rather start with our courthouse.
What do you mean?
I plan to be
Hu Xudong's defense lawyer.
He hasn't found a lawyer yet, has he?
The case files are still being studied.
How did you know I'd be handling his case?
No, I didn't.
So you'll be handling it?
I didn't know that until you told me.
Mentor,
we all know
lawyers face three major difficulties
when working on cases—
meeting clients,
reviewing files,
and investigating
and collecting evidence.
I'll try to figure
something out for the third problem.
But you can solve
the first two for me, right?
When will you go back to Beijing?
[Binjiang Station]
The local police station,
in collaboration with the railway police,
is strengthening patrols within
to sternly crack down on
theft, pickpocketing, and affray
in the station.
Once I settle everything down,
I'll come back.
If anything comes up,
call me anytime.
When you get home,
talk properly with your dad and Mr. Zhou.
Or maybe just tell them I pressured you
into this.
No need.
I know what to say to them.
Don't worry.
They'll be supportive.
Yizhong,
if you change your mind
when you get home,
just give me a call.
No need for any explanation.
I'll understand.
And I won't blame you.
My mind's set.
My mentor said, for me,
returning here
is like reclaiming lost land.
I'm back here for you,
but not entirely for you.
I've thought it through.
I just want to be back here.
Okay.
I'm taking off then.
Wait for me to come back.
I'll wait for you.
Please do.
Yizhong,
be careful and stay safe!
Captain Lyu,
what about that pager message?
What's your opinion on it?
What pager message?
You don't know?
At 11:31,
Yan Jicai sent a pager message
to his wife.
I really didn't know that.
Surveillance shows
that Yan Jicai's car
entered Gaoxin Road
at 11:15,
and then left at 11:57.
His car stayed on Gaoxin Road
for a total of 42 minutes.
From the parking spot
you identified
to the nearest public phone booth,
I studied the site myself and found
it is at least a six-minute trip.
Plus the time used to page his wife,
the whole thing would consume 13 minutes.
It took 2 minutes for Yan Jicai's car
to get on Gaoxin Road
and reach that parking spot,
which means he paused there
at 11:17.
Then he stayed
in the car for 8 minutes.
At 11:25, he got off the car
to find a phone
to send that pager message.
Thirteen minutes later,
namely
after 11:38, he got back
into the car.
Then it took 3 minutes for his car
to go from the parking spot
to the exit of Gaoxin Road.
That means
he started driving again at 11:54.
So, from the time he got back into the car
till he began driving again,
he only spent 17 minutes
in the car at most.
[Caiji Noodle House]
Boss, the pay's on the table.
Okay, take care!
Mom.
Mom!
What is it?
Go collect the money
on that table.
I'm busy now.
Mom.
Look,
that man's here again.
Ignore him. Go do your homework.
Eat up.
It's not poisoned.
Okay.
Nor did we spit in it.
The chili provided here is spicy.
Easy on it.
Liu Guiya.
I heard you're
still keeping that pager.
It was this pager message
that divided the period
of him being on Gaoxin Road
into two parts.
One was 8 minutes,
and the other 17 minutes.
Let's say he made the best
of those 17 minutes.
Do you think
he could commit that heinous crime
on the victim
within such a short time?
Could it be possible?
Anyone there?
Is anyone out there?
You've been keeping it
over all these years?
Of course I have to.
I'll keep it till you people regain
your conscience
and come to your senses.
[There are guests]
Have you shown it to our people?
Yes.
Who?
What's the name?
How did he look?
He didn't tell me his name.
Otherwise, I would've memorized it.
It was a young police officer,
with a mole on his right ear.
Can I borrow it?
No.
Lending it to me will do good
to you and your husband.
You think I'd trust you?
Liu Guiya,
do you really believe
your husband didn't do it?
Under this piece of land
lives a pig demon.
It eats our garbage every day
as it cultivates for immortality.
It can even recite
the multiplication table.
Do you believe that?
I'd rather believe this
than believe my husband
is a beast.
[Nanlu Public Security Bureau]
Captain Lyu,
got some free time today?
Where is Wang?
Section Chief Wang?
Maybe in the restroom.
Captain Lyu?
Free today?
Quick.
Take a seat.
What's up, Captain Lyu?
I'd like a word with Wang.
Please step out for a moment.
Okay.
Wang.
Do you remember
Yan Jicai's case
from years ago?
Well,
it was too long ago.
You went to his home
and saw
a pager message
his wife had received.
Did that happen?
I went several times.
But I was with
different co-workers on each trip,
including Li, Zhang,
and Wu.
All of them.
His wife only remembers you.
Is that so?
Then why wasn't it reflected
in the interrogation records?
When we discussed the case,
you never mentioned it either.
Captain Lyu,
you cannot blame this
on me.
What do you mean?
Have you forgotten?
At that time, who was
the first one to suggest
Yan Jicai
was the prime suspect?
It was you.
You kept urging us
to collect all evidence of his guilt.
So, by interviewing his wife,
I was completely following
your instructions at that time.
Are you saying
that you knew
this could be
exculpatory evidence
for Yan Jicai？
You didn't instruct us to collect
the evidence of his innocence as well.
You are also a police officer yourself.
When it comes to a criminal suspect,
we're supposed to collect evidence
of guilt,
as well as evidence
of mitigating circumstances or innocence.
Don't you know that?
Captain Lyu,
calm down.
Everyone respects you,
out of kindness.
But it's important for one
to know one's place.
You've already retired.
There's no need to dig up the past.
By clinging to an old case,
you'll only end up
hurting yourself. What's the point?
I've read the material
you submitted.
[Request to Initiate a Case Review]
Is it a case of yours?
No.
Then why did you
submit this material?
Why ask us to initiate
a case review?
Prosecutor Fang,
this case was brought up
by Bieshan Prison, where Yan Jicai
is serving time.
They think there are many doubts
about this case.
I took some time to look into it.
There are indeed some doubts.
I thought
we must protect our reputation,
since the case was handled
by our procuratorate.
Therefore,
I wrote this report.
You know who first dealt with
this case, right?
You should've talked to them first.
I did, on several occasions.
But they didn't see any problems.
How bold of you.
I guess you're doing this on purpose.
No, I'm not.
Aren't you worried about
offending others by handing in
a report directly to a supervisor?
I think they'd understand.
This is not exactly
a personal grudge.
To be honest,
I was in the Complaints
and Appeals Division at that time.
After this case was submitted,
I also found the evidence
problematic.
This case involves
too many departments
and officers.
There's no way we can cooperate
in initiating a case review.
However,
I, personally,
support you investigating it in private.
If you find solid evidence,
things will be easier.
If not,
there's still a way out.
How thoughtful of you, sir.
I... got it.
What was said in this room today
stays in this room.
You can do that, right?
If you don't trust me,
I'll just live in here then.
No way. Cut it out.
I'll sleep right here on the floor.
Not a chance.
Go away already.
I'm leaving then.
Captain Lyu,
what made you
want to look at this?
We don't have
the investigation subsidiary file here.
You know,
we have rules to follow.
Not just anyone
can access investigation subsidiary files.
Years ago, I was
in charge of this case.
Now the procuratorate
has raised an objection.
Why can't I read
the investigation subsidiary file?
I'll ask about it.
Chief Jiang,
Captain Lyu is with me now.
There's a matter...
Chief Jiang would like to see you.
Okay.
[Chief's Officer]
Mentor!
Why didn't you
tell me about your visit to the bureau?
Come on.
Take a seat.
Look at you,
still as grumpy as ever.
Still in a bad mood, huh?
I heard...
Siyi is able
to eat by herself now.
I'll bring my wife and kids to visit Siyi
in a few days.
Everything's fine.
Did you just beat up Wang?
It doesn't matter.
I've hated him for a long time.
He's incompetent
and loves kissing up.
Have some tea and calm down.
I only have one request.
I'd like to read
the investigation
subsidiary file of Yan Jicai's case.
Is that okay?
Those two prosecutors from Bieshan Prison
approached you, right?
This matter concerns no one else.
Mentor...
Those two prosecutors
are really persistent.
They've pulled strings
and written letters.
And now, they're trying to convince you.
I worked on
Yan's case with you.
Don't we know this case
better than anyone?
This is a waste of time, isn't it?
Do you know this?
Yan Jicai's car
once stopped
on Gaoxin Road.
He got out, found a phone booth,
and paged his wife.
I didn't know that.
See?
I also learned about it just now.
Where did you hear this?
I saw with my own eyes
the message on his wife's pager.
The time displayed can't be wrong.
We can check the records
at the paging station.
This lead is of great
importance,
yet that brat Wang Lin didn't
put it down in the interrogation records.
Now, you know
why I beat him up, right?
Mentor,
what can a pager message prove?
Do you remember?
At that time, we already determined
the car wasn't the primary crime scene.
It was the woods where the crime happened.
Do you know why my daughter
jumped off a building?
Because she was falsely accused
and couldn't see any way out.
Do you mean
we wrongly accused Yan Jicai?
I didn't say that.
But doesn't the omission
of such an important clue
as the pager message
from the interrogation records
mean that we made
a major oversight
when we dealt with this case?
Mentor,
I understand your concern.
But do you remember?
All of us were
under tremendous pressure
when working on this case.
It was returned
by the procuratorate and the court
for investigations several times,
causing rumors
everywhere in society.
People said we made a mistake.
We withstood enormous pressure
to finally bring Yan Jicai to court.
Do you remember that?
I've never forgotten it.
I'm asking to read the investigation
subsidiary file exactly because I am
having doubts now.
After the ruling was made,
all of us
got completely drunk.
You know better than anyone
about the huge effort we put into it.
You used to always tell me
that once a person
is a police officer for a day,
he or she will remain one forever.
So, Mentor,
you are not alone.
You are still
one of us.
You can't side with outsiders.
You just can't do that.
Come this way.
Wait a moment.
Mr. Zhou.
Mr. Zhou!
There are visitors.
For civil lawsuits, criminal cases,
inheritance, or divorces?
No.
They're prosecution officers,
saying that they're here for a matter.
Let them in then.
Quick, let them in.
Hello.
There you are.
Go make tea.
Have a seat.
T-That's lovely.
The cat knocked it over.
Here, tea for you.
-Thanks.
-Thank you.
Have some tea.
I'll leave you to talk.
Okay.
High blood sugar
makes me sleepy all the time.
Where are you...
I'm from Nanlu Procuratorate.
She's from Linshan Procuratorate.
You're here for Yan Jicai?
What a good memory you have.
I heard he had been
transferred to Bieshan Prison.
Disobedient, isn't he?
This guy, I'm telling you,
is utterly stubborn, and needs
to be taught a lesson.
You were
his defense lawyer years ago, right?
Yes, I was appointed by the court.
Mr. Zhou,
you were on the case for the entire time.
Do you notice
anything odd about it?
Just tell me straight
what you want to hear from me.
Anyway, my opinions
are all written in the defense statement.
You've read that,
haven't you?
Yes.
It's well written.
Of course it is.
Judging from
the first half of it,
it seems that you think he's innocent.
But the second half is an arguement
for a lighter sentence, saying that it was
Yan's first offense of a casual nature.
In addition,
you agree with the indictment
that the facts are basically clear
and the evidence conclusive.
Don't you think
these two parts are contradictory?
Are they?
Aren't they?
Yes, they are.
But the world
is made up of all sorts
of contradictions.
Are there any conflicts between you two?
N-No.
Maybe not now,
but there will be, probably.
How long have you two
been prosecutors?
You're not very young, are you?
You can't be that naive, right?
Though you were a court-appointed lawyer,
you had to be
responsible for your client, right?
That's a wrong way
to put it.
The task I initially received
was to plead for a lighter sentence
for Yan.
Because only in that way
could he stand a chance of living.
He got suspended death penalty
in the end.
That was good, wasn't it?
However, if I had gone against
the prosecution from the start
and pleaded not guilty for him,
he would very likely
have ended up with
an immediate execution.
As you said,
Yan Jicai rejected the lawyer
his wife got him
because he trusted you
and bet his whole life
on you.
But what happened?
Are you
setting up
a temporary moral court
in my office to judge me?
No, no. She's not.
Mr. Zhou,
this is definitely not what we mean.
Look, as you said just now,
you wanted to save Yan Jicai's life.
That's our aim too.
You see,
we're gathered here
for the same goal.
Now that's the right way to put it.
I defended him
simply based
on the content of the indictment.
As for my doubts,
I wrote them all
in the defense statement.
But the court didn't accept them.
So I chose to give up.
Why did you give up?
Because I had to live.
What's your surname?
Zhang.
Prosecutor Zhang,
let's suppose
I had carried out an investigation
and collected evidence,
and that the testimonies I got
were inconsistent with those obtained
by the police,
which
do you say the court
would opt for?
If facts are presented in court,
I don't believe
any judge would
disregard them
and make a wrong ruling.
You don't believe that?
Why don't you ask me
if I believe that?
What if they had said
I coerced the witnesses
into changing their testimonies?
What if I had been convicted
of witness tampering?
Those witnesses were all unreliable.
They could retract
their previous statements at any time.
I've tried cases long enough
to see plenty of those people.
Haven't I made enough mistakes
to learn better?
So you just chose to
sacrifice your own client?
I sacrificed him?
You think I did that?
Do you dare say
the same thing to the court
and the procuratorate?
We are no...
Got beaten again, didn't you?
No, they missed.
Thank God I ran fast enough.
But the truth is out now.
That braised meat shop
must be selling tainted pork.
She's no outsider. This is my daughter—
a reporter.
What a noble profession.
Hello.
No one in our family
does proper work.
Don't sell yourself short,
Zhou.
You've handled
a few miscarriages of justice.
When you are old,
I'll write memoirs for you.
The two of you don't
look like some defendant's family.
Are you the plaintiff?
We are prosecution officers.
[Liangcheng Law Firm]
Why is Mr. Zhou
being so resistant?
Every sentence he said
was a rhetorical question.
Lihui, haven't you noticed?
Noticed what?
Never mind.
What is it?
Did I... say anything wrong?
In fact, you asked no fewer questions
than he did.
Sometimes when you talk to me,
or even when you express your feelings,
you do the same thing.
Is it because you got used to
talking to prisoners
that way when you were
a resident prosecutor?
It has nothing to do with that.
Please don't be mad.
I'm not mad.
I think you're right.
I do have a problem in this regard.
I'll work on it.
It's okay.
Let's talk to Qiao Xiaojun again.
He definitely hasn't told us everything.